The Forever War. Goes On
Hearts and Minds is a documentary, war film directed by Peter Davis.
Many times during his presidency, Lyndon B.
Johnson said that ultimate victory in the Vietnam War depended upon the U.S.
military winning the "hearts and minds" of the Vietnamese people.
Filmmaker Peter Davis uses Johnson's phrase in an ironic context in this anti-war documentary, filmed and released
while the Vietnam War was still under way, juxtaposing interviews with military figures like U.S.
Army Chief of Staff William C.
Westmoreland with shocking scenes of violence and brutality.
Self - Aide to President Truman 1946-50, played by Clark Clifford.
Self (archive footage), played by John Foster Dulles.
Self - French Foreign Minister in 1954, played by Georges Bidault.
Self (archive footage), played by Harry S. Truman.
Self (archive footage), played by Dwight D. Eisenhower.
Self (archive footage), played by John F. Kennedy.
Hearts and Minds is a 1974 American documentary film about
the Vietnam War directed by Peter Davis.
The film's title is based on a quote from President Lyndon B.
Johnson: "the ultimate victory will depend on the hearts and
minds of the people who actually live out there".
It won the Oscar for Best Documentary at the 47th
Academy Awards presented in 1975.
The film premiered at the 1974 Cannes Film Festival.
Commercial distribution was delayed in the United States due to legal issues, including a temporary restraining order obtained by one of the interviewees, former National Security Advisor Walt Rostow, who
had claimed through his attorney that the film was "somewhat misleading" and "not representative" and that he had not been given the opportunity to approve the results of his interview.
Columbia Pictures refused to distribute the picture, which forced the
producers to purchase back the rights and release it by other means.
The film was shown in Los Angeles for the one week it needed to be
eligible for consideration in the 1974 Academy Awards.
In 2018, the film was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library
of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam veteran,
vietnam, war veteran, prisoner of war.
The tone is dark.